A Finding Aid to the Burt Chernow Papers, 1930-2002, in the Archives of American Art AAA.cherburt
Archives of American Art
- Research Material for Christo and Jeanne-Claude: A Biography, 1930-2002; Series 1; 17.1 Linear feet Boxes 1-17, 23, OV 24
  - Photographs, 1930-2001; 1.8; 0.5 Linear feet Box 17, 23
    - Personal Photographs (Box 17)
      - Christo and Jeanne-Claude, circa 1962-1965 (Box 17, Folder 19)
        Some photographs include artworks from this period.
      - Christo and Jeanne-Claude, circa 1980-1989 (Box 17, Folder 20)
      - Christo and Jeanne-Claude in Westport, Conn., 1984 (Box 17, Folder 21)
      - Christo Family Photographs, circa 1930-1980 (Box 17, Folder 22)
      - Jeanne-Claude Family Photographs, circa 1937-1994 (Box 17, Folder 23)
      - Javacheff Family Visiting the United States, 1985-1997 (Box 17, Folder 24)
      - Tom Golden, circa 1991 (Box 17, Folder 25)
      - Copy Negatives, circa 1988-2001 (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - Project Photographs (Box 17)
      - Early Drawings by Christo, circa 1984-1997 (Box 17, Folder 27)
      - Gallery Installations, circa 1962 (Box 17, Folder 28)
      - Galerie Lauhus Exhibition, 1961 (Box 17, Folder 29)
      - 42390 Cubic Foot Package (Minneapolis), 1966 (Box 17, Folder 30)
      - Air Package (Eindhoven), 1966 (Box 17, Folder 31)
      - Artist's Key Club (New York City), 1965 March 12-13 (Box 17, Folder 32)
      - Central Park Gates (New York City), 1980 (Box 17, Folder 33)
        Contains photographic reproductions of drawings.
      - Dockside Packag e (Cologne Harbor), 1961 (Box 17, Folder 34)
      - Iron Curtain (Paris), 1961-1962 (Box 17, Folder 35)
      - Kassel Air Package, 1967-1968 (Box 17, Folder 36)
      - MCA Chicago Wrapped, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 37)
      - Mastaba (Abu Dhabi), 1981 (Box 17, Folder 38)
      - Pont Neuf Wrapped, ca. 1985 (Box 17, Folder 39)
      - Running Fence, 1975-1976 (Box 17, Folder 40)
      - Store Fronts, 1965-1976 (Box 17, Folder 41)
      - Surrounded Islands, circa 1983 (Box 17, Folder 42)
        Oversized photograph in Box 23.
      - Three Blind Mice (Holland), 1968 (Box 17, Folder 43)
      - Umbrellas, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 44)
      - Valley Curtain, 1971-1972 (Box 17, Folder 45)
      - Various Packages, 1961-1997 (Box 17, Folder 46)
      - Various Wrapped Buildings, 1961-1988 (Box 17, Folder 47)
      - Whitney Museum of American Art, Packed, crica 1960-1969 (Box 17, Folder 48)
        Contains a photograph of a drawing only.
      - Wrapped Australian Coast, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 49)
      - Wrapped Books and Magazines, 1970-1988 (Box 17, Folder 50)
      - Wrapped Cans and Bottles, 1958-1960 (Box 17, Folder 51)
      - Wrapped Car (Milan), 1963 (Box 17, Folder 52)
      - Wrapped Monuments, circa 1970-1976 (Box 17, Folder 53)
      - Wrapped Oil Barrels, 1958-1959 (Box 17, Folder 54)
      - Wrapped Reichstag, 1980-1995 (Box 17, Folder 55)
      - Wrapped Walkways (Kansas City, Mo.), 1977-1979 (Box 17, Folder 56)
      - Wrapped Women, 1963-1968 (Box 17, Folder 57)
      - Pre-project Hearings, circa 1980-1995 (Box 17, Folder 58)
    - Oversized Photographs from Box 17, Folder 42 (Box 23)
  - Fabric Samples, 1983-1995; 1.9; 1 Folders Box 17
    Series contains fabric samples from the four projects of the Christos undertaken during the period in which Burt Chernow was working with them, including Wrapped Pont Neuf (1985), Umbrellas Japan (1991), Umbrellas California (1991), Surrounded Islands (1983), and Wrapped Reichstag (1995).
    - Fabric Samples, circa 1983-1995 (Box 17, Folder 59)
- Other Writings, 1962-1999; Series 2; 1.5 Linear feet Boxes 17-19
  This series contains drafts of writings by Burt Chernow other than his biography of Christo and Jeanne-Claude. Most of his writings are in the form of articles, reviews, and lectures. Some writing projects include significant material in addition to drafts, including a lengthy unpublished article on the artist Arman, which includes drafts, research, and a 1993 interview with the artist on one sound cassette. Other writings with significant additional material include multiple pieces on Jean Woodham along with notes and research, and a lengthy article on Francisco Zuniga with three transcripts of interviews with the artist and research material collected for the article. Material found with drafts for a book on Milton Avery drawings include correspondence with Sally Avery and a draft of her preface to the book, as well as numerous photographs of Avery's artwork. Also common among the articles in the series are reviews of exhibitions held in Connecticut during the 1980s, and essays written for many exhibition catalogs. Art education and public art are also common subjects among Chernow's writings in this series.
  Additional writings about the Christos found in this series include lectures by Chernow on Surrounded Islands, Umbrellas, and Wrapped Reichstag. These writings are particularly significant because they are projects undertaken while Chernow was following the Christos closely during his research for the biography, and also because they are projects that Chernow had not yet covered in the biography at the time of his death, so the lectures represent his only completed writings on these projects. Found with the Wrapped Reichstag text is a video recording of Burt and Ann Chernow delivering this lecture in Westport. Lectures also include multiple talks given on art education and public art earlier in Chernow's career, and a lecture written for a traveling exhibition "12 Soviet Artists", shown in Westport, Conn. in 1976.
  Poetry by Burt and Ann Chernow, as well as teaching notes, syllibi, and résumés are also found in this series. Writings by others include two lengthy typescripts of lectures on art education by Howard Conant, who was Chernow's teacher, as well as articles by others about Christo, and an interview with Burt Chernow by Brazilian journalist Georgia Lobacheff.
  Series is arranged by type of material, articles are arranged alphabetically by subject, and lectures are arranged by title. Published versions of many of the books and articles in this series are found in series 4, printed material.
  - Address Book, circa 1985-1995 (Box 17, Folder 60)
  - Calendar, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 61)
  - Book, Milton Avery Drawings (Box 17)
    - Drafts, circa 1976-1982 (Box 17, Folder 62)
    - Photographs, circa 1976-1982; 1 of 3 folders (Box 17, Folder 63)
  - Book, Milton Avery Drawings (Box 18)
    - Photographs, circa 1976-1982; 2 of 3 folders. (Box 18, Folder 1-2)
    - Research, circa 1976-1982 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Articles (Box 18)
    - Ronald Abbe, circa 1980-1989 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - "Abe Ajay: A Perfect Universe", 1978-1979 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - "Arman's Public Sculpture," Early Drafts, circa 1993 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - "Arman's Public Sculpture," Final Drafts, circa 1993 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - "Arman's Public Sculpture," Interview with Arman, circa 1993; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - "Arman's Public Sculpture," Research, circa 1993 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Artist's Rights, 1976-1977 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - "'Art Resources' for New Audiences", circa 1970-1979 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Arts Education, circa 1964-1985 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - "March Avery", 1993 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - "Milton Avery on Paper", circa 1973 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - "Milton Avery: A Singular Vision", circa 1987 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - "Branko Babunek", circa 1990-1997 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Christo Text for Wadsworth Atheneum, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Christo's Wrapped Coast at Westport Weston Art Center, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - "Community Identity through Public Art", circa 1974 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - "Elba Damast", 1980-1989 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - "In Homage to James H. Daugherty", circa 1975 (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Dictionary of Art Entries, 1992-1994 (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - Stephan Dohanus, circa 1980 (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - Herzl Emanuel, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - "Ending the Great Silence: Women Artists Entering the Eighties", circa 1980 (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - "Getting Behind the Barnes Curtain", circa 1965-1980 (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - "Duane Hanson's More Real than Real Sculpture", circa 1975 (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - "David Hayes: Screen Tests", circa 1990 (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - Barkley Hendricks, circa 1983-1984 (Box 18, Folder 29)
      Includes letters and an exhibition catalog.
    - "Hilla Rebay's Kandinskys", 1989 (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - "The Housatonic Museum of Art: A Prototype the Explores the Potential of the Visual Arts in a Community College Education", circa 1970-1979 (Box 18, Folder 31)
    - "In Praise of Connecticut Artists", circa 1983 (Box 18, Folder 32)
    - "An Interview with Lee Doo-Shik", 1991 (Box 18, Folder 33)
    - Lester Johnson, circa 1975; 1996 (Box 18, Folder 34)
      Contains a letter from Howard Conant.
    - "Kawashima: A Timeless Universal Eroticism", circa 1967 (Box 18, Folder 35)
    - "Victor Keppler In Retrospect", circa 1970 (Box 18, Folder 36)
    - "Nicholas Krushenick", circa 1981 (Box 18, Folder 37)
    - "Richard Lindner's Female Predator", circa 1978 (Box 18, Folder 38)
    - "Harry McCormick", circa 1975 (Box 18, Folder 39)
    - "A Mixed Bag", circa 1980 (Box 18, Folder 40)
    - "Model Cities" Culture and Recreation Component, circa 1970 (Box 18, Folder 41)
    - "The New X Factor", circa 1980 (Box 18, Folder 42)
    - Claes Oldenburg, circa 1976 (Box 18, Folder 43)
    - Gabor Peterdi, circa 1978-1982 (Box 18, Folder 44)
    - Protecting J. Alden Weir's Farm and Our Artistic Heritage", circa 1982 (Box 18, Folder 45)
    - Jim Reed, circa 1980 (Box 18, Folder 46)
    - Reviews of Group Exhibitions, circa 1975-1985 (Box 18, Folder 47)
    - "Barbara Roux: Mysterious Realities", circa 1975 (Box 18, Folder 48)
    - "Larry Silver", circa 1975 (Box 18, Folder 49)
    - "Some Guidelines for Coping with Auctions", circa 1975 (Box 18, Folder 50)
    - "Peter Voulkos and Peter Callas", circa 1980 (Box 18, Folder 51)
    - "Jean Woodham: Pioneer", circa 1991-1996 (Box 18, Folder 52)
    - Francisco Zuñiga, circa 1978-1985 (Box 18, Folder 53)
  - Lectures (Box 18)
    - "12 From the Soviet Underground", 1976 (Box 18, Folder 54)
    - "Adieu Hou U.," Retirement Speech by Burt Chernow, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 55)
    - "Art in the Public Domain", 1978 (Box 18, Folder 56)
    - Introduction to Christo at Aldrich Museum, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 57)
    - Introduction to Lowell Weicker Commencement Address, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 58)
    - "The Jerusalem Windows", circa 1962 (Box 18, Folder 59)
    - "Man of the Cloth," Lecture on Christo, 1992; 1 Sound cassettes includes transcript and flyers (Box 18, Folder 60)
    - On Surrounded Islands, circa 1983 (Box 18, Folder 61)
    - On Art Collecting, circa 1980 (Box 18, Folder 62)
  - Lectures (Box 19)
    - Slide Lecture Given During Pont Neuf Wrapped, 1985 September (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Umbrellas Talk, circa 1991 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - "Wrapping the Reichstag", 1995; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) Includes transcripts, flyers, and letters (Box 19, Folder 3-5)
  - Letter to Editor, 1994 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Poetry, circa 1986 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Résumés, 1978-1986 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Teaching Material, 1960-1984 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - By Others (Box 19)
    - "Christo and Jeanne-Claude" by Bob Schroeder, 1995 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - "How to Start and Fund a Public Art Collection" by D. Murphy Wagner, circa 1980 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Interview with Burt Chernow by Georgia Lobacheff, 1995 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Unpublished Article on Christo by Joey Lenti, 1996-1999 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - "An Interview with Artist Bernard Riley" by Sharon Greytak, circa 1970 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - "Odd Man In" on Nicholas Kruschenick, by Ann Chernow, circa 1975 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - "Poet on the Moon: A Dialogue on Liberal Education in the Community College" by Donald Tighe, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - "On the Education of Artists" by Howard Conant, 1965 (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - "The Pursuit of Excellence" by Howard Conant, 1963 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Oversized Galley from Box 17, Folder 62 (Box 23)
- Organizational Records, 1963-2000; Series 3; 1.1 Linear feet Boxes 19-20, 23, OV 24
  Organizational records document Chernow's affiliations with organizations, primarily in Connecticut, for which he worked, or in which he served as an officer or member. Records include correspondence, catalogs, clippings, yearbooks, notes, writings, and photographs. Records are found related to Housotanic Community College (which later became Housatonic Community Technical College) where Chernow taught, the Housatonic Museum of Art, founded by Chernow, multiple projects of the Westport arts advisory council, the Westport Arts Center, the Westport schools permanent art collection committee, and the Westport Weston arts council. The bulk of records are for the Westport arts awards, organized by the Westport arts advisory council, which include correspondence, notes, writings, photographs, event invitations, and financial records. The "One Percent for the Arts Ordinance" file documents Chernow's advocacy for the ordinance in correspondence with town representatives, drafts of the ordinance, and collected documents relating to a similar "Art in Architecture" program from 1977. Records for the Housatonic Community College include yearbooks from three of the years Chernow taught there, with multiple photographs of him marked within them. A photograph of Chernow with Governor Rowland of Connecticut is also found relating to the construction of the Bridgeport facility for the Housatonic College in 1997. A small file is also found for Connecticut Fine Arts, Chernow's art dealership business, containing letters and a database printout of artworks.
  See also series 2, Other Writings, for Chernow's retirement speech from HCC and a file of teaching materials.
  - Art Communication International, 1995 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Art Education Organizations, 1963-1977 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Conecticutt Fine Arts, 1983-1991 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Connecticutt Humanities Council, circa 1980 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Housatonic Community College (Box 19)
    - Bridgeport Facility, circa 1997 (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - Catalogs, 1986-1970 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - Clippings, circa 1997 (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence, 1968-1997 (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - Yearbook, 1969 (Box 19, Folder 27)
    - Yearbook, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - Yearbook, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Housatonic Museum of Art (Box 19)
    - Catalogs and Poster, 1980-2000 (Box 19, Folder 30)
      Oversized poster in OV 24.
    - Clippings, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 31)
      Oversized laminated clipping in Box 23.
    - Dedication of Burt Chernow Galleries, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 32)
    - Exhibitions, circa 1980-1986 (Box 19, Folder 33)
    - Television Publicity, circa 1985 (Box 19, Folder 34)
    - Writings, circa 1980-1997 (Box 19, Folder 35)
  - International Association of Art Critics Press Pass, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 36)
  - Westport Arts Advisory Council (Box 19)
    - Clippings, circa 1990 (Box 19, Folder 37)
    - Notes and Correspondence, circa 1994 (Box 19, Folder 38)
    - One Percent for Art Ordinance, 1995; 1977 (Box 19, Folder 39)
    - Public Art Conservation, 1992-1996 (Box 19, Folder 40)
    - Westport Arts Awards, 1994-1995 (Box 19, Folder 41-42)
    - Westport Arts Awards, 1994-1995 (Box 20, Folder 1-3)
    - Westport Arts Awards, 1995-1996 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Westport Arts Awards, 1996-1998 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Westport Arts Awards Photographs, 1994-1997 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Westport Arts Center (Box 20)
    - Advocacy, 1976-1996 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Architectural Plans, 1996 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Programs, 1986-1996 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Westport Schools Permanent Art Collection Committee, 1993-1996 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Westport Weston Arts Council, 1985-1986 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Oversized Laminated Clipping from Box 19, Folder 31 (Box 23)
  - Oversized Poster from Box 19, Folder 30. (Box OV 24)
- Printed Material, 1960-2002; Series 4; 1.3 Linear feet Boxes 20-21, 23
  Drafts of articles and books in this series are found in series 2, Other Writings. Printed materials related to Chernow's research on the Christos' biography, are found in series 1: Research Material on Christo and Jeanne-Claude: A Biography.
  - Articles by Burt Chernow (Box 20)
    - Untitled Articles, circa 1970-1997 (Box 20, Folder 12-14)
    - "The Westport Art Collection," in Art Education, 1966 December (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - "Gabor Peterdi" in Arts Magazine, 1977 March (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - "Lester Johnson" in Arts Magazine, 1977 November (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - "Richard Lindner" in Arts Magazine, 1978 May (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - "Abe Ajay" in Arts Magazine, 1978 December (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - "Harry McCormick" in Arts Magazine, 1983 December (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - "Zuñiga's Memoriable Images" in Four Winds, 1981 Winter (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - "Figure Drawing - Upper Grades" in Grade Teacher, 1962 October (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - "What Is Art?" in Grade Teacher, 1961 September (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - "The Tranquil World of Will Barnet" in FairFields, 1979 November (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - "Lester Johnson and the Kaleidoscopic Crowd" in Intellect, 1977 April (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - "The College Art Collection" in Junior College Journal, 1968 September (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - "Housatanic Museum...Enhancing Quality" in Community and Junior College Journal, 1983 February (Box 20, Folder 27)
    - "Lester Johnson in New York and P-town" in Provincetown Arts, 1996 (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - "Elementary Art" in School Arts, 1965 December (Box 20, Folder 29)
    - "An Interview with Antonio Frasconi" in School Arts, 1966 May (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - Article with Photograph by Burt Chernow in New York Times Magazine, 1961 August 27 (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - Books by Burt Chernow (Box 20)
    - Green Farms Cooks Tour 1962 (Box 20, Folder 32)
      Burt Chernow, Art Editor
    - Paint, Paper, and Stuff: Art Activities I, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 33)
    - Paint, Paper, and Stuff: Art Activities II, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 34)
  - Books by Burt Chernow (Box 21)
    - Milton Avery Drawings, 1973 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Lester Johnson: The Kaleidoscopic Crowd, 1975 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Gabor Peterdi: Paintings, 1982 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Bahunek, 1998, 2002 (Box 21, Folder 4)
      Contains explanatory note written by Ann Chernow in 2002. Item is a photocopy.
  - Book by Burt and Ann Chernow, ABC, 1996 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Books by Don Celender (Box 21)
    - Political Art Movement, Religious Art Movement, Affluent Art Movement, Academic Art Movement, Corporate Art Movement, Organizational Art Movement, Cultural Art Movement, Mass Media Art Movement, 1970-1971 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Observation and Scholarship Examination for Art Historians, Museum Directors, Artists, Dealers, and Collectors, 1975 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Film Catalogs, circa 1977 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Publisher's Catalogs, Taplinger, 1986-1987 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Clippings, 1962-1983 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Clippings, 1983-1996 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Clippings, About Burt Chernow, 1960-1998 (Box 21, Folder 12-14)
  - Clippings, Reviews of Burt Chernow's Books, 1983-1985 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Clippings, About Westport, Conn., circa 1960-1990 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Exhibition Announcements, 1982-1997 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Exhibition Announcements with Text by Burt Chernow, 1980-1983 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, 1975-1982 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Exhibition Catalogs with Burt Chernow Artwork, 1989; 1974 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Exhibition Catalogs with Text by Burt Chernow (Box 21)
    - Abe Ajay: Selections 1964-1978 (1978) (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - March Avery: Selected Works 1974-1994 (1994) (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - Will Barnet: Twenty Years of Painting and Drawing (1979-1980), 1980-1981 (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - Christo (1978) (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - Contemporary Graphics, circa 1985 (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - Taller del Ojo: Elba Damast (1984) (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - Herzl Emanuel: Sculpture and Drawing (1988-1989) (Box 21, Folder 27)
    - David Hayes, circa 1990 (Box 21, Folder 28)
    - Barkley L. Hendricks, 1967-1987 (1988) (Box 21, Folder 29)
    - Lester Johnson, 1975; 1998 (Box 21, Folder 30)
    - Kandinsky from the Hilla von Rebay Foundation Collection (1989) (Box 21, Folder 31)
    - Gabor Peterdi, 1988; 1996 (Box 21, Folder 32)
    - Harvey Weiss: Sculpture (1996) (Box 21, Folder 33)
    - Jean Woodham: 50 Years of Sculpture (1996-1998) (Box 21, Folder 34)
    - Francisco Zuñiga, 1978; 1980 (Box 21, Folder 35)
  - Flyers and Press Releases, 1970-1996 (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - Obituaries and Memorials for Burt Chernow, 1997-1998 (Box 21, Folder 37)
  - Oversized Magazine from Box 20, folder 31 (Box 23)
- Photographs, 1950-1997; Series 5; 0.8 Linear feet Boxes 21-23
  Photographs by Ann and Burt Chernow are filed first in the series, followed by photos of the Chernows alone and with artists. Photographs by other photographers are filed at the end of the series, with known photographers listed in the folder listing. Because photographs are arranged by photographer, note that there are multiple photographs of some artists filed in different places in this series, such as Mary Bauermeister, Lester Johnson, Paul Jenkins, Gabor Peterdi, and Christo.
  Additional photographs are found in series 1, 2, and 3. See series descriptions for more details.
  Series includes many photographs of artists taken by the Chernows, as well as photographs collected but not taken by them, and many of these are signed and dedicated to Ann and Burt Chernow by the artists. Most of the signed photographs were framed when donated, with a note that they had hung in Burt Chernow's office. These photographs were taken out of their frames during processing, but most remain matted.
  A few photographs of Burt and Ann Chernow are also found, along with photographs of them with artists such as Mary Bauermeister and the Christos. Several of the photographs by the Chernows come with negatives and contact sheets as well. Some of the photographs of artists not credited to the Chernows may in fact have been taken by them, but are not credited, or do not include evidence of their production such as negatives or contact sheets for identification.
  Also found in this series are photographs of a bust of Chernow by an unidentified artist, and photocollages by Burt Chernow, one of which is labled, "Burt's last work of art."
  - Photographs of Artists by Ann Chernow, Lester Johnson, circa 1995; circa 1980 (Box 21, Folder 38)
  - Photographs of Artists by Burt Chernow (Box 21)
    - Mary Bauermeister, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 39)
    - Alexander Calder, circa 1985 (Box 21, Folder 40)
      Oversized photograph in box 23.
    - Christo, 1983 May (Box 21, Folder 41)
    - Paul Camacho, circa 1989 (Box 21, Folder 42)
    - Bob Cottingham, circa 1985 (Box 21, Folder 43)
    - Mary Frank, circa 1985 (Box 21, Folder 44)
    - Ben Johnson, circa 1980 (Box 21, Folder 45)
    - Guy Johnson, circa 1975 (Box 21, Folder 46)
    - John Marshall, circa 1980 (Box 21, Folder 47)
    - Robert Natkian, circa 1980 (Box 21, Folder 48)
      Oversized contact sheet in Box 23.
    - Alfonso Ossorio, 1982 (Box 21, Folder 49)
      Oversized contact sheets in box 23.
    - Gabor Peterdi, 1993 (Box 21, Folder 50)
    - Lee Savage, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 51)
  - Photographs of Burt and Ann Chernow, circa 1970-1997 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Photographs of the Chernows with Artists (Box 22)
    - Paul Cadmus, 1995 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Nicholas Krushenick, circa 1995 (Box 22, Folder 3)